<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>
<API>
    <MODULE name="NativeTabbar" parent="Rho" generateUnderscoreRubyNames="true">
        <HELP_OVERVIEW>The NativeTabbar methods let you use multiple instances of the RhoMobile webview in separate tabs. </HELP_OVERVIEW>
        <MORE_HELP>On Android, iOS and WIndows Phone 8 the tabs are true Native Tabbar controls to give your application a native look and feel.No more than 4 tabs can be created in the Windows Phone 8 tabbar. A tabbar separator doesn't exist in Windows Phone 8. On Windows Mobile/CE there are no visible tabs. Either Tabbar or Toolbar should be used in an application - Tabbar and Toolbar shouldnot be used simultaneously.
## Enabling the API
This API is part of the `coreapi` extension that is included automatically.
    :::ruby
    extensions: ["coreapi"]

## JavaScript Usage
Be sure to review the [JavaScript API Usage](/guide/api_js) guide for important information about using this API in JavaScript.

## Ruby Usage
Be sure to review the [Ruby API Usage](/guide/api_ruby) guide for important information about using this API in Ruby.
        </MORE_HELP>
        <MORE_HELP_EB>On Android, the tabs are true Native Tabbar controls to give your application a native look and feel. On Windows Mobile/CE there are no visible tabs, but can be used in conjunction with shortcuts to run multiple 'applications' from a single instance. Either Tabbar or Toolbar should be used in an application - Tabbar and Toolbar shouldnot be used simultaneously.
## Enabling the API
There are two methods of enabling the NativeTabbar API:

* Include all ebapi modules or
* Include only the API modules you need

For either of these methods, you'll need to include files from the `/Enterprise Browser/JavaScript Files/Enterprise Browser` directory on the computer that you installed the Enterprise Browser.

### Include all JS API modules
To include all JS APIs, you must copy the ebapi-modules.js file to a location accessible by your app's files and include the JavaScript file in your app. For instance, to include the modules file in your index.html, with the file in the same directory as your index.html, you would add the following line to the &lt;head&gt; section of your index.html:

    :::html
    &lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="utf-8" src="ebapi-modules.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

> Note: that the pathing for this file is relative to the current page.

This will define the EB class within the page. Any page you need to use the modules will need to have the .js file included in this fashion.

### Include only the modules you need
To include single APIs, you must first include the `ebapi.js` in your HTML as well as the API file you want to use. For instance, to use the NativeTabbar API, I would add the following code to my HTML file(s), assuming the API files have been copied to the same directory as the HTML.

    :::html
    &lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="utf-8" src="ebapi.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript" charset="utf-8" src="eb.nativetabbar.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

The ebapi.js file is necessary for all single API inclusions.
        </MORE_HELP_EB>

        <TEMPLATES>
        </TEMPLATES>

        <PROPERTIES access="STATIC" generateAccessors="false">
        </PROPERTIES>

        <METHODS  access="STATIC">
            <ALIASES>
                <ALIAS new="get_current_tab" existing="currentTabIndex" deprecated="true"/>
            </ALIASES>

            <METHOD name="create" hasCallback="optional" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Removes the current tabbar and replaces it with this one. Callback will be called when tab is switched.  Whilst the actual number of tabs you can create will depend on the memory available on your device there is an absolute upper limit of 30 tabs in any one application.</DESC>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="tabElements" type="ARRAY">
                        <DESC>Array of Tab elements.</DESC>

                        <PARAM name="tabElement" type="HASH">
                            <DESC>Properties of Tab elements.</DESC>
                            <PARAMS>
                                <PARAM name="label" type="STRING">
                                    <DESC>Visible label to display on the tabbar.</DESC>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="action" type="STRING"  rhoAction="true">
                                    <DESC>URL to page which will be loaded into tab. Predefined actions are not supported. It may be path to Ruby controller action; i.e. '/app/Account' would load the Account index action. For ruby callback use 'callback:/app/Account' Or javascript method to call: 'javascript: methodOnTab();'. Or path to html page to load.</DESC>
                                    <DESC_EB>URL to page which will be loaded into tab. It may be JavaScript method to call: 'javascript: methodOnTab();'. Or path to html page to load.</DESC_EB>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="icon" type="STRING">
                                    <DESC>Relative path to tabbar item icon in your application; typically located in /public/images/.</DESC>
                                    <DESC_EB>Icon Relative path (from Enterprise Browser application) to local files on the device. </DESC_EB>
                                    <PLATFORM>Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
                                    <PLATFORM_EB>Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="reload" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                    <DESC>When tab is activated  - page in tab will be reloaded.</DESC>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="selectedColor" type="INTEGER">
                                    <DESC>Change the selected color of this tab. On Android this works only if you setup selectedColor for all tabs and also setup backgroundColor for the whole Tabbar. This property change background color on Android and _icon's_ color on iOS according to the platform's UI-style specifications.</DESC>
                                    <DESC_EB>Change the selected color of this tab. On Android this works only if you setup selectedColor for all tabs and also setup backgroundColor for the whole Tabbar. This property change background color on Android according to the platform's UI-style specifications.</DESC_EB>
                                    <PLATFORM>Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
                                    <PLATFORM_EB>Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="disabled" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                    <DESC>Tab will be displayed as disabled.</DESC>
                                    <PLATFORM>Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
                                    <PLATFORM_EB>Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="backgroundColor" type="INTEGER">
                                    <DESC> Background color for tab. Use when your application background color is not white for removing blink during switch tabs.</DESC>
                                    <PLATFORM>Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
                                    <PLATFORM_EB>Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                                </PARAM>
                                <PARAM name="useCurrentViewForTab" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                    <DESC>Gives a smooth transfer to a newly opened tab from the current view into this Tab and make this Tab active. Only one Tab can have this parameter.</DESC>
                                    <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Win32, Android, iOS</PLATFORM>
                                    <PLATFORM_EB>WM, CE, Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                                </PARAM>

                                <PARAM name="perishable" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                    <DESC>Sets whether this tab is allowed to be destroyed when a memory limit is reached (Windows Mobile)</DESC>
                                    <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                                </PARAM>

                                <PARAM name="createOnInit" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                    <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                                    <DESC>Create tab immediately when TabBar is created. Action also will be executed. If false, the tab will be created when it is switched to. Don't use this parameter on the devices with a small amount of RAM.</DESC>
                                </PARAM>
                            </PARAMS>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAM>

                    <PARAM name="tabBarProperties" type="HASH">
                        <DESC>Properties of TabBar.</DESC>
                        <PARAMS>
                            <PARAM name="verticalOrientation" type="BOOLEAN" default="false" productException="eb">
                                <DESC>Creates a vertical tabbar on the iPad.</DESC>
                                <PLATFORM>iOS</PLATFORM>
                            </PARAM>
                            <PARAM name="backgroundColor" type="INTEGER">
                                <DESC>Background color of the tabbar.</DESC>
                                <PLATFORM>Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
                                <PLATFORM_EB>Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
                            </PARAM>
                            <PARAM name="hiddenTabs" type="BOOLEAN" default="true">
                                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                                <DESC>Do not display Tabs with labels.Only hiddenTab=true is currently supported.</DESC>
                            </PARAM>
                            <PARAM name="createOnInit" type="BOOLEAN" default="false">
                                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                                <DESC>Create tabs immediately when TabBar is created. Action also will be executed. If false, then each tab will be created when first switch to the tab is executed. Don't use this parameter on the devices with a small amount of RAM.</DESC>
                            </PARAM>
                            <PARAM name="placeTabsBottom" type="BOOLEAN">
                                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                                <DESC>Place TabBar to bottom instead of default top - only for Android.</DESC>
                            </PARAM>
                        </PARAMS>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>

                <CALLBACK type="HASH">
                    <DESC>Information about tab changes.</DESC>
                    <PARAMS>
                        <PARAM name="tab_index" type="INTEGER">
                            <DESC>New tab index.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="newTabIndex" type="INTEGER">
                            <DESC>New tab index.</DESC>
                            <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="oldTabIndex" type="INTEGER">
                            <DESC>New tab index. If you switched to first activated tab, when oldTabIndex will be -1, which means that there was no old tab index exists.</DESC>
                            <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="tabEvent" type="STRING">
                            <DESC></DESC>
                            <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                            <VALUES>
                                <VALUE value ="onTabFocus">
                                    <DESC>Fires when a tab gains focus.</DESC>
                                </VALUE>
                                <VALUE value ="onTabNewError">
                                    <DESC>Fires when a new tab cannot be created.</DESC>
                                </VALUE>
                            </VALUES>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAMS>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="currentTabIndex">
                <DESC>Returns the current tab 0-based index.</DESC>
                <RETURN type="INTEGER">
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="remove" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Removes all tabbar except the default tabbar whose index value is 0. Does nothing if there is no active tabbar other than tab 0.</DESC>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="removeTab" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Removes the Tab by index. Method will remove the WebView for the specific tab, it will not remove the tab from the tab array, so all indexes will remain the same.You cannot delete the tab with useCurrentViewForTab flag.If you switch to previously removed tab, tab will be recreated.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="tabIndex" type="INTEGER">
                        <DESC>The index for tab (index numbered from 0) to delete.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="setTabBadge" runInThread="ui" productException="eb">
                <DESC>Set the iPhone badge to tab.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>iOS</PLATFORM>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="tabIndex" type="INTEGER">
                        <DESC>The index for this tab (index numbered from 0). You can also set -1 to select current tab for set badge.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                    <PARAM name="badge" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>String for iPhone badge, such as '12'.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="switchTab" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Switch active tab.</DESC>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="tabIndex" type="INTEGER">
                        <DESC>The index for this tab (index numbered from 0).</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="isCreated" generateDoc="false">
                <DESC>If Tabbar already created.</DESC>
                <RETURN type="BOOLEAN"/>
            </METHOD>

        </METHODS>

        <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
        <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Win32, Android, iOS, WP8</PLATFORM>
        <PLATFORM_EB>WM, CE, Win32, Android</PLATFORM_EB>
        <REMARKS>
            <REMARK title="Device Limitations With Multiple Tabs">
                <DESC>Please consider the limitations of the device when creating multiple tabs with the Native TabBar. The number of tabs that can be created will depend on the resources of the device and the complexities of the pages displayed in those tabs but, as a general rule, a maximum of 10 tabs on an MC75a should be enforced. Also consider setting the `createOnInit` property to false so that not all tabs are initialized when the TabBar is first created and using the in-process engine for a more responsive experience.</DESC>
            </REMARK>
        </REMARKS>
        <EXAMPLES>
           <EXAMPLE title="Create native tabbar">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Create a platform-native tabbar. Tabs can link to internal application links (such as those built with "url_for") as well as external URLs.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
def create_tabbar
    Rho::NativeTabbar.create([{
      :label => "Home",
      :action => url_for(Rho::Application.startURI)
      },
      {
      :label => "example.com",
      :action => "http://www.example.com",
      }], {}, url_for(:action => :tabbar_callback)
    )
end

def tabbar_callback
    Alert.show_popup("Switching to tab #{@params["rab_index"]}")
end
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
function create_tabbar() {
    Rho.NativeTabbar.create([{
            label: "Home",
            action: "/app"
        }, {
            label: "example.com"
            action: "http://www.example.com"
        }], {}, tabbar_callback
    );
}

function tabbar_callback(params) {
    alert("Switching to tab "+params["tab_index"]);
}
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Switch tab">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Switch the active tab.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
# Make the third tab active
Rho::NativeTabbar.switchTab(2);
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
// Make the third tab active
Rho.NativeTabbar.switchTab(2);
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Remove tabbar">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Remove the tabbar.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
Rho::NativeTabbar.remove
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
Rho.NativeTabbar.remove();
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
        </EXAMPLES>
    </MODULE>
</API>
