<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>
<API>
    <MODULE name="Instrumentation" parent="Rho" generatedoc="false">
        <HELP_OVERVIEW>The Instrumentation module can be used to simulate key presses, touch events, file events and capturing of the screen.</HELP_OVERVIEW>
        <MORE_HELP>The Instrumentation module will be available to any process that requests it.  No properties are defined, only methods.</MORE_HELP>
    
        <TEMPLATES>
            <SINGLETON_INSTANCES/>   <!-- produce enumerate() fabric method, all instances is singletones by ID, add ID property -->
            <DEFAULT_INSTANCE/> <!-- object has default static property, all methods can be call by static way (called from default instance), produce default(), set_default() methods -->
            <PROPERTY_BAG/> <!-- object has properties, produce getProps(), setProps() methods -->
        </TEMPLATES>

        <METHODS>
            <METHOD name="simulate_key_event_code" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Simulates a single key event, based upon the supplied parameter.</DESC>
    
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="keycode" type="INTEGER">
                        <DESC>The character that will be pushed onto the input stream for the underlying OS.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>
    
            <METHOD name="simulate_key_event_string" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Simluates a string, based upon the supplied paramter.</DESC>
				
				<PARAMS>
					<PARAM name="str" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>The string that will be pushed onto the input stream for the underlying OS.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
				</PARAMS>
            </METHOD>
			
            <METHOD name="simulate_touch_event" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Simulate a touch event, this can either be a left down, left down and mouse move and left up. To draw something correctly, this function must be called multiple times by the user.
                For instance, when drawing a line, the first call will be to be mouse down, then the second call will be to mouse move, and the final call will be to mouse up.
                This will draw line.  You cannot pass through an array of co-ordinates or button presses.</DESC>
				
				<PARAMS>
					<PARAM name="event_type" type="INTEGER">
						<DESC>The event type represents the state of the touch event and where it is on the screen.
						Currently, the three values that can be used are 0, 1 and 2.
						</DESC>
					</PARAM>
					<PARAM name="x" type="INTEGER">
						<DESC>The absolute x co-ordinate, cannot be negative.</DESC>
					</PARAM>
					<PARAM name="y" type="INTEGER">
						<DESC>The absolute y co-ordinate, cannot be negative.</DESC>
					</PARAM>
				</PARAMS>
            </METHOD>
			
			<METHOD name="screen_capture" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Capture the contents of the screen and save it.  On WMCE it is a Bitmap.</DESC>
				<PARAMS>
					<PARAM name="pszFilename" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>The name of the file to be used for saving the screen buffer.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
				</PARAMS>
				
				<RETURN type="INTEGER">
                    <DESC>The result of the screen capture method. -1 for failure and 1 for success.</DESC>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>
			
			<METHOD name="get_allocated_memory">
                <DESC>Return the amount of memory that the process is using.  Currently on Windows, this just returns the amount of 
				memory the device has, on Android, it can return size of the running process.
				</DESC>
				
				<RETURN type="INTEGER">
                    <DESC>A value greater than 0.</DESC>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>
			
			<METHOD name="delete_file" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Delete the file at the specified location.</DESC>
				<PARAMS>
					<PARAM name="str" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>The name of the file to be deleted.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
				</PARAMS>
				
				<RETURN type="INTEGER">
                    <DESC>-1 if deletion fails, 1 if deleted</DESC>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>
			
			<METHOD name="file_exists" runInThread="none">
                <DESC>Delete the file at the specified location.</DESC>
				<PARAMS>
					<PARAM name="str" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>The name of the file to search for.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
				</PARAMS>
				
				<RETURN type="INTEGER">
                    <DESC>-1 if error occured, 0 if file not found, 1 if file found.</DESC>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>
			
			<METHOD name="re_simulate_navigation">
                <DESC>Generate, PB_ONMETA and PB_NAVIGATE messages</DESC>
            </METHOD>
        </METHODS>
        
        <USER_OVERVIEW>
            <!--  More conversational style with INLINE SAMPLES, written in MarkDown -->
            <![CDATA[
TODO. Add example code to show how to call methods.
    				]]>
    
        </USER_OVERVIEW>
        <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
        <PLATFORM>
            <!--  This section is used for the supported platform images at the top -->
        </PLATFORM>
    </MODULE>
</API>    
