<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>
<API>
    <MODULE name="Barcode" parent="Rho">
0
        <ALIASES>
            <ALIAS new="Barcode" deprecated="true"/>
        </ALIASES>

        <HELP_OVERVIEW>The Barcode Module provides access to control the functionality of the device's scanner. Because RhoMobile Suite is designed to run on both Consumer devices and Symbol Technologies' enterprise devices support for the Barcode API will vary for each method and properties depending on which platform you are running on. Please note that a lot these APIs are optimized for the extended functionality that Symbol Technologies devices provide. Check the platform indicators in each property or method section. In general if you are developing for a consumer device the number of symbologies available to you will be limited to just the most common ones, eg EAN13, UPCA etc and your scanning will be via the device camera. If your application is running on Symbol Technologies' hardware you will have much finer control over a more fully featured Scanner, often with a choice of scanner hardware on the device. In general if you wish to capture a single barcode in a 'one shot' use case, eg your App just wants to capture a single barcode to be submitted to a price comparison website then use Barcode.take(callback); if your application is expecting a number of barcodes to be received, common in enterprise scenarios for example a user in a warehouse then use Barcode.enable(callback). The Barcode API will not run on non-Symbol Technologies Windows Mobile / CE devices.Only the foreground application is given access to the scanning hardware, when an application is sent to the background its state will be saved and it will automatically relinquish control of the scanner. When brought back to the foreground, an application previously using the barcode API will have its previous configuration reapplied automatically.In VC70 scanner will work only if connected in SSI Mode. In  Symbol android devices, it is recommended to use EMDK for KitKat devices and not to use EMDK in JellyBean devices.</HELP_OVERVIEW>

        <HELP_OVERVIEW_EB>The Barcode Module provides access to control the functionality of the device's scanner. Check the platform indicators in each property or method section. In general if you are developing for a device with only a camera, the number of symbologies available to you will be limited to just the most common ones, eg EAN13, UPCA etc and your scanning will be via the device camera. If your application is running on more traditional Symbol Technologies' hardware you will have much finer control over a more fully featured Scanner, often with a choice of scanner hardware on the device. In general if you wish to capture a single barcode in a 'one shot' use case, eg your App just wants to capture a single barcode to be submitted to a price comparison website then use Barcode.take(callback); if your application is expecting a number of barcodes to be received, common in enterprise scenarios for example a user in a warehouse then use Barcode.enable(callback). Only the foreground application is given access to the scanning hardware, when an application is sent to the background its state will be saved and it will automatically relinquish control of the scanner. When brought back to the foreground, an application previously using the barcode API will have its previous configuration reapplied automatically. A VC70 scanner will work only if connected in SSI Mode.
        </HELP_OVERVIEW_EB>

        <MORE_HELP>
## Enabling the API
In order to use this API you must include the following extension in your `build.yml`
    :::ruby
    extensions: ["barcode"]

The `barcode` extension is also included automatically if you specify the following in your `build.yml`
    :::ruby
    app_type: "rhoelements"

NOTE: If you are building a Windows Mobile or Windows CE app with this API, you must set your app_type as "rhoelements" in your build.yml as shown [here](../guide/build_config#other-build-time-settings).

## JavaScript Usage
Be sure to review the [JavaScript API Usage](/guide/api_js) guide for important information about using this API in JavaScript

## Ruby Usage
Be sure to review the [Ruby API Usage](/guide/api_ruby) guide for important information about using this API in Ruby
        </MORE_HELP>       
        <TEMPLATES>
            <!-- <SINGLETON_INSTANCES/>    produce enumerate() fabric method, all instances is singletons by ID, add ID property -->
            <DEFAULT_INSTANCE/> <!-- object has default static property, all methods can be call by static way (called from default instance), produce default(), set_default() methods -->
            <PROPERTY_BAG/> <!-- object has properties, produce getProps(), setProps() methods -->
        </TEMPLATES>

        <PROPERTIES usePropertyBag="accessorsViaPropertyBag">
            <DESC>These properties are used to configure the barcode scanner or barcode decoding algorithms, depending on your device.</DESC>
            <PROPERTY name="autoEnter" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android,WP8</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, automatically appends the character code for 'enter' to the end of any barcodes scanned. This is useful if you want to submit forms following a scan without further interaction. This property will only take effect if you have not specified a callback to the enable method. AutoEnter and AutoTab are mutually exclusive properties.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="autoTab" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, automatically appends the tab character to the end of any barcodes scanned. This is useful if you are populating a form and want to jump to the next field in the form without further interaction. This property will only take effect if you have not specified a callback to the enable method. AutoTab and AutoEnter are mutually exclusive properties.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="hapticFeedback" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true" default="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Controls the haptic feedback on decode. This means that if this is set to true, then the device will vibrate when a decode occurs.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="linearSecurityLevel" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Describes the linear security level used during decoding. This determines the number of times a barcode must be read before it is decoded. If the successive reads of the barcode do not match, it will not be decoded.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="REDUNDANCY_AND_LENGTH" value="redundancyAndLength">
                        <DESC>Double redundancy based on redundancy flags and code length. Only applicable to laser scanners, not BlockBuster imager scanners. Not supported on Android with EMDK version 3.1 and above.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="SHORT_OR_CODABAR" value="shortOrCodabar">
                        <DESC>Double redundancy if short barcode or Codabar.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="LONG_AND_SHORT" value="longAndShort">
                        <DESC>Double redundancy for long barcodes, triple for short barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="ALL_TWICE" value="allTwice">
                        <DESC>Double redundancy for all barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="ALL_THRICE" value="allThrice">
                        <DESC>Triple redundancy for all barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="scanTimeout" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Maximum time in milliseconds that laser scanners will emit a beam or imager scanners will enable the imager. A value of 0 indicates an infinite timeout. This parameter is compatible with aimType:trigger, aimType:timedHold, aimType:timedRelease and aimType:pressAndRelease. Note that for regulatory reasons scanTimeout is not configurable on all laser / imager scanners. Scan timeout is extent to hardware capabilities and limitations.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rasterMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <DESC>Describes the type of vertical rastering to use.</DESC>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="RASTER_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>No vertical rastering.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RASTER_OPEN_ALWAYS" value="openAlways">
                        <DESC>Vertical rastering is always full open. To adjust the rastering height use the rasterHeight property.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RASTER_SMART" value="smart">
                        <DESC>Vertical rastering mode is 'Smart'.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RASTER_CYCLONE" value="cyclone">
                        <DESC>Vertical rastering mode is 'Cyclone'.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rasterHeight" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Vertical rastering height to use, as a percentage, when rasterMode:openAlways is applied. This value must be between 0 and 100.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="aimType" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Describes the type of aiming to use.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_TRIGGER" value="trigger">
                        <DESC>Standard trigger mode. Holding the trigger will start a decoding session.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_TIMED_HOLD" value="timedHold">
                        <DESC>Aiming lasts for the time specified by 'timedAimDuration' before decoding. The opportunity to scan will last until the barcode is decoded or scanTimeout occurs.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_TIMED_RELEASE" value="timedRelease">
                        <DESC>Aiming lasts until trigger is released. If the timedAimDuration has expired when the trigger is released then a decode session is started until a barcode is decoded or for the remaining time equal to the scanTimeout value.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_PRESENTATION" value="presentation">
                        <DESC>Provided to support Kiosk devices. The scanner illuminates when movement is detected in the range of the scanner window. In order to use this mode the scanner must be initiated with a softscan using the Rho.Barcode.start() method and again after each decode. The device must be equipped with a sensor to detect movement to use presentation mode. MK31XX devices come with presentation mode pre-enabled in the scanner driver and the aimType cannot be modified for these devices.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_PRESS_AND_RELEASE" value="pressAndRelease">
                        <DESC>Scan will continue after the trigger is released until scanTimeout occurs.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMTYPE_CONTINUOUS_READ" value="continuousRead">
                        <DESC>Once the trigger is pulled barcodes will continue to be scanned as long as the trigger is held, enabling rapid scanning, to be used in conjunction with sameSymbolTimeout and differentSymbolTimeout. This value is ignored if viewfinderMode is set to 'dynamicReticle'</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="timedAimDuration" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Aim duration in milliseconds for aimType:timedHold and aimType:timedRelease.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="sameSymbolTimeout" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When the aimType:continuousRead property is applied this value defines the interval between which the same barcode can be decoded twice. The value is specified in milliseconds, use 0 to indicate no interval between successive reads. Use this value to prevent accidental duplicate scans.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="differentSymbolTimeout" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When the aimType:continuousRead property is applied this value defines the interval between which different barcodes can be scanned. The value is specified in milliseconds, use 0 to indicate no interval between successive reads. Use this setting to allow time for the operator to re-aim the device between successive scans.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="aimMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Defines the aiming mode to use.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMMODE_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>No Aiming (Can be overridden by picklistMode).</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMMODE_DOT" value="dot">
                        <DESC>Laser barcode readers will show a dot for aiming.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMMODE_SLAB" value="slab">
                        <DESC>Laser barcode readers will show a slab for aiming.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="AIMMODE_RETICLE" value="reticle">
                        <DESC>Imager barcode readers will show a reticle for aiming.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="picklistMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Imager / Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Allows the imager to decode only the barcode that is directly under the cross-hair / center of the reticle. This feature is most useful in applications where multiple barcodes may appear in the field of view during a decode session and only one of them is targeted for decode. When enabled picklistMode will override aimMode or, if no aiming is chosen, and use aimMode:reticle. This mode will also interact with viewfinderMode, see the EMDK for C help file for more information. Enabling picklist mode may adversely affect overall decoding performance.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="PICKLIST_DISABLED" value="disabled">
                        <DESC>Disables picklist mode so any barcode within the field of view can be decoded.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="PICKLIST_HARDWARE_RETICLE" value="hardwareReticle">
                        <DESC>Enables picklist mode so that only the barcode under the projected reticle can be decoded. On Windows, if the imager does not support a projected reticle then the behavior is the same as softwareReticle. On Android, this is only supported for Imager (non-viewfinder) based scanners.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="PICKLIST_SOFTWARE_RETICLE" value="softwareReticle">
                        <DESC>Enables picklist mode so that only the barcode in the center of the image is decoded. This is most useful when used in conjunction with static and dynamic reticle viewfinder modes. This value is not supported on Android Platform.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Configures the mode of the scanner viewfinder window. This attribute is not supported on all Scanners and will interact with the picklistMode parameter, see the EMDK for C help file for more information.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="VIEWFINDER_ENABLED" value="enabled">
                        <DESC>Only the viewfinder is enabled (not the reticle). Displays a viewfinder on the screen showing the image being captured by the camera.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="VIEWFINDER_DISABLED" value="disabled">
                        <DESC>The viewfinder will not be displayed during aiming or scanning.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="VIEWFINDER_STATIC_RETICLE" value="staticReticle">
                        <DESC>Displays the viewfinder as well as draws a red reticle in the center of the image which helps with tracking the barcode.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="VIEWFINDER_DYNAMIC_RETICLE" value="dynamicReticle">
                        <DESC>Displays the viewfinder as well as draws a red reticle in the center of the image. If the barcode in the image is 'decodable' the reticle turns green to indicate this. This mode requires a second trigger press to decode the barcode after the reticle turns green. Not supported on Android.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderX" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When scanning a barcode using a Camera scanner the viewfinder preview window will appear this number of pixels from the left hand side of the screen. The images displayed in the viewfinder will be scaled as appropriate.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderY" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When scanning a barcode using a Camera scanner the viewfinder preview window will appear this number of pixels from the top of the screen. The images displayed in the viewfinder will be scaled as appropriate.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderWidth" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When scanning a barcode using a Camera scanner the viewfinder preview window will be this number of pixels wide. The images displayed in the viewfinder will be scaled as appropriate.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderHeight" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When scanning a barcode using a Camera scanner the viewfinder preview window will be this number of pixels in height. The images displayed in the viewfinder will be scaled as appropriate.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderFeedback" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Configures the feedback given after a successful scan. This value is ignored if aimType is set to continuousRead and no feedback will be given. Not supported on Android with EMDK version 3.1 and above.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="VF_FEEDBACK_ENABLED" value="enabled">
                        <DESC>The last image that was successfully decoded is displayed. The time for which the image is displayed can be configured by the viewfinderFeedbackTime parameter.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="VF_FEEDBACK_DISABLED" value="disabled">
                        <DESC>No feedback is given in the viewfinder after a successful decode.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="VF_FEEDBACK_RETICLE" value="reticle">
                        <DESC>The last image that was successfully decoded is displayed along with a red reticle in the center of the image. The time for which the image is displayed can be configured by the viewfinderFeedbackTime parameter.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="viewfinderFeedbackTime" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If the viewfinderFeedback:enabled or viewfinderFeedback:reticle are applied then the decoded barcode will remain on the screen for this duration, specified in milliseconds. Not supported on Android with EMDK version 3.1 and above.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="focusMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Imager / Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the focus mode in use.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="FOCUS_FIXED" value="fixed">
                        <DESC>Use fixed focus.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="FOCUS_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Use auto focus.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="illuminationMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Imager / Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Selects the illumination mode to use. Not currently supported on Android (illumination is always on).</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="ILLUMINATION_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Auto-exposure algorithms will decide whether illumination is required. Not currently supported on Android.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="ILLUMINATION_ALWAYS_ON" value="alwaysOn">
                        <DESC>External illumination is always on.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="ILLUMINATION_ALWAYS_OFF" value="alwaysOff">
                        <DESC>External illumination is always off.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="dpmMode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Imager / Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices. The scanning engine must support DPM barcodes.</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Allows Direct Part Marking (DPM) barcodes to be read When true, but may adversely affect overall decoding performance. DPM is a way of stamping barcodes directly on physical objects and is only available on DPM terminals.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="inverse1dMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices. The scanning engine must support inverse barcodes</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Allows the user to select inverse 1D barcodes for decoding.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="INVERSE_ENABLED" value="enabled">
                        <DESC>Inverse 1D symbology decoding is enabled.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="INVERSE_DISABLED" value="disabled">
                        <DESC>Inverse 1D symbology decoding is disabled.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="INVERSE_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Allows decoding of both positive and inverse 1D symbologies.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="poorQuality1dMode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Imager / Camera Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Allows poor quality 1D barcodes to be read When true, but this will adversely affect the overall decoding performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="beamWidth" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the width of the laser beam. All devices will support normal beam widths but other widths may not be supported on your device.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="BEAM_NORMAL" value="normal">
                        <DESC>Laser beam width is normal.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="BEAM_WIDE" value="wide">
                        <DESC>Laser beam width is wide.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="BEAM_NARROW" value="narrow">
                        <DESC>Laser beam width is narrow.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="dbpMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Describes the type of Digital Bar Pulse (DBP) being produced by the scan engine.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="DBP_NORMAL" value="normal">
                        <DESC>Tells the scan engine to produce normal DBP.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="DBP_COMPOSITE" value="composite">
                        <DESC>Tells the scan engine to produce composite DBP, which is 2 different sets of DBP data multiplexed together for better decode performance. In order to enable this mode it must be supported by the scanner.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="klasseEins" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the Klasse Eins laser on time function.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="adaptiveScanning" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables adaptive scanning. When set to true, the scan engine will automatically toggle between 2 scan angles, wide and narrow, allowing the scan engine to decode barcodes both in close proximity and far away (~100 inches). Adaptive scanning is only supported in high performance, long working range scan engines such as SE960.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="bidirectionalRedundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Laser Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables bidirectional redundancy.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="barcodeDataFormat" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Camera / Imager Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the format in which the barcode data is returned, binary data is returned in Data URI format with the appropriate mime type. This parameter is designed to be used primarily with image based symbologies (eg. Signature). Binary data will not be output as keystrokes, you must set a decode callback in order to receive scanned data.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="FORMAT_BINARY" value="binary">
                        <DESC>Scanned data will be returned in Data URI format.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="FORMAT_TEXT" value="text">
                        <DESC>Scanned data will be returned in Text format.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="dataBufferSize" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the number of bytes allocated to receive the scanned barcode. This parameter is designed to be used primarily with image based symbologies and should not be modified unless absolutely necessary (eg. Signature).</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="connectionIdleTimeout" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Bluetooth Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the time, in seconds, that an external scanner will be allowed to remain idle before the connection is terminated to conserve power.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="disconnectBtOnDisable" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Bluetooth Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Forces the scanner to disconnect from the terminal when it is 'disabled'. Since the scanner is disabled when you navigate to a new page, set this value to false if you want to maintain the bluetooth connection to your remote scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="displayBtAddressBarcodeOnEnable" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Bluetooth Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If set to true the bluetooth address will be displayed as a barcode on the screen during the pairing process, initiated by calling 'enable' on a bluetooth scanner. Not all devices support this functionality. Note you must specify this parameter before or within the call to 'enable'.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="enableTimeout" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Bluetooth Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Configures the time (in seconds) allowed to pair with the external bluetooth scanner after calling the 'enable()' method. You must specify this parameter before calling 'enable' to change the default.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="friendlyName" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Returns the friendly name associated with the scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="lcdMode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true" default="false">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Controls whether LCD Mode is enabled on the scanner. LCD Mode makes it easier to scan barcodes off of LCD screens (like mobile device screens)</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="lowBatteryScan" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true" default="false">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Set to false to disable scanning when the battery is low / critical or set to true to enable it.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="triggerConnected" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true" default="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Only applies to an enabled laser or imaging scanner. Disconnecting the trigger will prevent the scan beam from being emitted, this can temporarily prevent a user from scanning without having to disable the scanner, which can take longer. By default the trigger will be connected when the scanner is first enabled, you do not have to connect it separately. Please note that disconnecting the trigger will also prevent the start method from emitting a laser. This property will only affect the scanner and will have no effect on the 'captureTrigger' API.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="disableScannerDuringNavigate" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true" default="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>By default if you have enabled the Scanner on a page, through either JavaScript or Ruby and navigate to a new page the Scanner will automatically disable. To override this behavior you can set this option to false and once enabled the Scanner will remain so in the foreground application until you disable it.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="decodeVolume" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true" default="5">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The volume of the device beeper when a barcode is scanned. Volume specified using 0 to 5, with 5 being the loudest. The value of 0 is device dependent, some Windows Mobile / CE devices interpret this as the quietest volume; if you wish to completely disable the beeper on scan please set decodeSound to an empty or invalid sound file.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="decodeDuration" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true" default="250">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The duration of the device beeper when a barcode is scanned, in milliseconds.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="decodeFrequency" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true" default="3000">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The frequency of the device beeper when a barcode is successfully decoded. This should be within the range of the beeper but the API will accept values in the range 0 to 65535.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="invalidDecodeFrequency" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true" default="2500">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The frequency of the device beeper when a barcode is scanned but not successfully decoded. This should be within the range of the beeper but the API will accept values in the range 0 to 65535.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="decodeSound" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Path to a local wave file to be played when the scanner successfully decodes a barcode. This setting overrides the scanner beeper. In Android, this settings will not override beeper and hence not supported.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="invalidDecodeSound" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Path to a local wave file to be played when a barcode is scanned but not successfully decoded. This setting overrides the scanner beeper.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="scannerType" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, WP8, WIN32</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="false">All Scanners</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The type of scanner in use, will be one of 'Camera', 'Imager' or 'Laser'. Camera scanners capture and process an image taken via the devices camera. Imager scanners rely on capturing and processing an image of the barcode via dedicated scanning hardware. Both camera and imager scanners are capable of decoding 1D and 2D barcodes. Laser scanners are only capable of decoding 1D barcodes and rely on a sweeping laser.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="allDecoders" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="false">Scanners on Symbol Technologies' devices</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When set to true, the barcode scanner will read all barcode types that the scanner is capable of reading. When set to false, the barcode scanner will not be able to decode any symbologies, this is most useful if you want to set the scanner to a default state before only enabling your required symbologies. The fewer symbologies that are enabled the faster the decoding performance of the scanning engine will be. This property will return true only if all supported symbologies by the scanner are enabled, if only a subset of supported symbologies are enabled then false will be returned. Note that some decoders will not be enabled as some symbologies use the same systems to encode data, making it impossible to differentiate between them. For example: "canpostal" and "auspostal" both use a 4-state system, so devices will only enable either "canpostal" OR "auspostal" when "alldecoders" is enabled. Note that other symbologies also share the 4-state system.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="aztec" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Aztec barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="chinese2of5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Chinese 2of5 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabar" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Codabar barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabarClsiEditing" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables Codabar CLSi formatting when set to true.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabarMaxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Codabar barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabarMinLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Codabar barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabarNotisEditing" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables Codabar NotisEditing formatting when set to true.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="codabarRedundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Codabar Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Code11 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11checkDigitCount" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies whether to verify 0, 1 or 2 check digits.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE11_CHECKDIGIT_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Scanning engine will verify no Code 11 check digits.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE11_CHECKDIGIT_ONE" value="one">
                        <DESC>Scanning engine will verify one Code 11 check digit.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE11_CHECKDIGIT_TWO" value="two">
                        <DESC>Scanning engine will verify two Code 11 check digits.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Code 11 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Code 11 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 11 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code11reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned Code 11 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Code128 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128checkIsBtTable" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, decodes concatenated Code128 output only if the pair belongs to one of the commonly concatenated pairs as defined by the standard.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128ean128" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, barcodes with the EAN128 subtype property set will be read.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128isbt128" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, barcodes with the isbt128 subtype property set will be read.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128isbt128ConcatMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code128 ISBT concatenation mode property. This feature allows a pair of barcodes which meet certain criteria defined in the ISBT128 spec to be reported as a single barcode. This parameter describes the different concatenation modes available for ISBT128.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE128ISBT_NEVER" value="never">
                        <DESC>Will ignore the barcode pair and only output decode data for one of the barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE128ISBT_ALWAYS" value="always">
                        <DESC>Will not decode if both barcodes are not present or if one of them can not be decoded.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="CODE128ISBT_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Auto-Discriminate.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Code 128 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Code 128 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128other128" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the other 128 property which enables the non EAN and non ISBT 128 subtype.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 128 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code128securityLevel" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 128 security level and accepts a value between 0 and 3 inclusive. 0: Allows the scanner to operate in its most aggressive state, while providing sufficient security in decoding most 'in-spec' barcodes. 1: Eliminates most mis-decodes. 2: Select this option if security level 1 fails to eliminate mis-decodes. 3: Select this option if security level 1 and 2 fail to eliminate mis-decodes. Be advised that selecting level 3 is an extreme measure against mis-decoding and will significantly impair the decoding ability of the scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="compositeAb" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Composite AB barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="compositeAbUccLinkMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Describes whether UCC link mode is enabled.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="UCC_NEVER" value="never">
                        <DESC>Link flag is ignored.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UCC_ALWAYS" value="always">
                        <DESC>Composite AB barcodes are always linked.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UCC_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Auto-discriminate whether Composite AB barcodes are linked.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="compositeAbUseUpcPreambleCheckDigitRules" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>This setting causes the UPC rules specified in the UPC EAN parameters to be used when reporting composite decode data.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="compositeC" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Composite C barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Code 39 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39code32Prefix" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables reporting of the Code32 prefix when a Code39 barcode is converted.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39convertToCode32" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables conversion from Code39 to Code 32 barcodes, when set the decoded barcode is converted to Code 32.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39fullAscii" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables full ASCII conversion of Code 39 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Code 39 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Code 39 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 39 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables reporting of the Code 39 check digit when a Code 39 barcode is scanned.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39securityLevel" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 128 security level and accepts a value between 0 and 3 inclusive. 0: This setting allows the scanner to operate in its most aggressive state, while providing sufficient security in decoding most 'in-spec' barcodes. 1: This setting eliminates most mis-decodes. 2: Select this option if security level 1 fails to eliminate mis-decodes. 3: Select this option if security level 1 and 2 fail to eliminate mis-decodes. Be advised that selecting level 3 is an extreme measure against mis-decoding and will significantly impair the decoding ability of the scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code39verifyCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Turns on verification of the Code 39 check digit.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code93" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Code 93 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code93maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Code 93 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code93minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Code 93 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="code93redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Code 93 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="d2of5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for D2of5 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="d2of5maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a D2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="d2of5minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a D2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="d2of5redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the D2of5 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="datamatrix" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Datamatrix barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ean13" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for EAN 13 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ean8" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for EAN 8 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ean8convertToEan13" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, EAN 8 barcodes will be converted to EAN 13 and EAN 13 parameters used.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for I2of5 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5convertToEan13" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, EAN 8 barcodes will be converted to EAN 13 and EAN 13 parameters used.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a I2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a I2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the I2of5 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned I2of5 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="i2of5verifyCheckDigit" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables the verification of the I2of5 check digit.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="I2OF5_VERIFY_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Disables verification of the check digit.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="I2OF5_VERIFY_USS" value="uss">
                        <DESC>Enables the USS format for the check digit.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="I2OF5_VERIFY_OPCC" value="opcc">
                        <DESC>Enables the OPCC format for the check digit.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="korean3of5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Korean 3of5 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="korean3of5redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets Korean 3of5 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="korean3of5maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Korean 3of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="korean3of5minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Korean 3of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroPdf" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Macro PDF barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroPdfBufferLabels" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the scanner driver will return  he barcode data only after the complete macroPdf sequence has been read. If false, the scan driver will return each barcode in the macroPdf sequence as it is read.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroPdfConvertToPdf417" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, MacroPDF barcodes will be converted to PDF417 codes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroPdfExclusive" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the scanner driver will not complete read requests while in the middle of a macroPdf sequence. Once a macroPdf sequence has been started it must be completed or canceled before the scan driver will complete other read requests.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroMicroPdf" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for MacroMicroPDF barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroMicroPdfBufferLabels" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the scanner driver will return the barcode data only after the complete macroMicroPdf sequence has been read. If false, the scanner driver will return each barcode in the macroMicroPdf sequence as it is read.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroMicroPdfConvertToMicroPdf" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, MacroMicroPDF barcodes will be converted to MicroPDF codes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroMicroPdfExclusive" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the scanner driver will not complete read requests while in the middle of a macroMicroPdf sequence. Once a macroMicroPdf sequence has been started it must be completed or canceled before the scan driver will complete other read requests.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="macroMicroPdfReportAppendInfo" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the appended info is concatenated to the decoded data before being returned.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="matrix2of5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Matrix 2of5 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="matrix2of5maxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a Matrix 2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="matrix2of5minLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a Matrix 2of5 barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="matrix2of5reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned Matrix 2of5 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="matrix2of5verifyCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables verification of the Matrix 2of5 symbology check digit.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="maxiCode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Maxicode barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="microPdf" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Micro PDF barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="microQr" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Micro QR barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msi" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for MSI barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiCheckDigits" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the number of MSI check digits to use.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="MSI_CHECKDIGITS_ONE" value="one">
                        <DESC>Use one check digit for MSI barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="MSI_CHECKDIGITS_TWO" value="two">
                        <DESC>Use two check digits for MSI barcodes.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiCheckDigitScheme" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the check digit scheme used to verify MSI barcodes.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="MSI_CHECKDIGITS_MOD11" value="mod11">
                        <DESC>The first check digit is MOD 11, the second is MOD 10.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="MSI_CHECKDIGITS_MOD10" value="mod10">
                        <DESC>Both check digits are MOD 10.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiMaxLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the maximum number of allowable characters in a MSI barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiMinLength" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the minimum number of allowable characters in a MSI barcode. If your application only expects barcode lengths in a certain range, reducing the allowed range can improve scanning performance. Allowed values are 0 to 55.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiRedundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the MSI Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="msiReportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned MSI barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="pdf417" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for PDF 417 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="signature" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Signature barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance. Signature barcodes return their data in Data URI format, it is recommended you adjust the dataBufferSize and barcodeDataFormat properties when scanning Signature barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="signatureImageHeight" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the output height of the captured signature barcode. Signature barcodes return their data in Data URI format, it is recommended you adjust the dataBufferSize and barcodeDataFormat properties when scanning Signature barcodes. Provide a number greater than or equal to 20.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="signatureImageWidth" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the output width of the captured signature barcode. Signature barcodes return their data in Data URI format, it is recommended you adjust the dataBufferSize and barcodeDataFormat properties when scanning Signature barcodes. Provide a number greater than or equal to 20.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="signatureImageQuality" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the output quality of the captured signature barcode. Signature barcodes return their data in Data URI format, it is recommended you adjust the dataBufferSize and barcodeDataFormat properties when scanning Signature barcodes. Provide a value between 10 and 100 inclusive.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ausPostal" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Australian Postal barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="canPostal" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Canadian Postal barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="dutchPostal" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Dutch Postal barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="japPostal" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Japanese Postal barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ukPostal" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for UK Postal barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="ukPostalReportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned UK Postal barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="us4state" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for US 4-State barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="us4stateFics" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for US 4-State FICS barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="usPlanet" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for US Planet barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="usPlanetReportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned US Planet barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="usPostNet" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for US Post Net barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="usPostNetReportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned US Post Net barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="qrCode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for QR Code barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="gs1dataBar" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for GS1 DataBar barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance. This symbology was previously known as rss.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="gs1dataBarExpanded" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for GS1 Databar Expanded barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance. This symbology was previously known as rssExp.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="gs1dataBarLimited" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for GS1 Databar Limited barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance. This symbology was previously known as rssLim.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="tlc39" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for TLC 39 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="trioptic39" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Trioptic 39 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="trioptic39Redundancy" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Trioptic 39 Redundancy property, if set the barcode must be decoded twice before being accepted. This will slow scanning but improve reliability.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanBookland" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables decoding of UPC EAN Bookland barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanBooklandFormat" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specifies the bookland format to use when decoding UPC EAN Bookland barcodes.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="BOOKLAND_ISBN10" value="isbn10">
                        <DESC>Causes 978 bookland barcodes to be reported in 10 digit mode.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="BOOKLAND_ISBN13" value="isbn13">
                        <DESC>Causes 978/979 bookland barcodes to be transmitted as EAN13 as per 2007 ISBN-13 protocol.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanConvertGs1dataBarToUpcEan" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.1.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, RSS barcodes will be converted to UPC/EAN format. For this setting to work UPC/EAN symbologies must be enabled.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanCoupon" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables decoding of UPC EAN Coupon barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanLinearDecode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the linear decode property.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanRandomWeightCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, enables random weight check digit verification.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanRetryCount" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the retry count for auto-discriminating for supplementals. The value must be between 2 - 20 inclusive.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanSecurityLevel" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Sets the Security level for decoding UPC EAN barcodes and accepts a value between 0 and 3 inclusive. 0: This setting allows the scanner to operate in its most aggressive state, while providing sufficient security in decoding most 'in-spec' barcodes. 1: This setting eliminates most mis-decodes. 2: Select this option if security level 1 fails to eliminate mis-decodes. 3: Select this option if security level 1 and 2 fail to eliminate mis-decodes. Be advised that selecting level 3 is an extreme measure against mis-decoding and will significantly impair the decoding ability of the scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanSupplemental2" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, enables the supplemental barcode decoding. Note you must have upcEanSupplementalMode:always set for this parameter to take effect.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanSupplemental5" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, enables the supplemental barcode decoding. Note you must have upcEanSupplementalMode:always set for this parameter to take effect.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcEanSupplementalMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Describes the UPC EAN Supplemental mode.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Supplementals are ignored.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_AUTO" value="auto">
                        <DESC>Auto-discriminates supplementals.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_ALWAYS" value="always">
                        <DESC>Will not decode upc/ean without supplementals.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_SMART" value="smart">
                        <DESC>The decoder will return the decoded value of the main block right away if it does not belong to any of the supplemental types. If the barcode starts with one of the prefixes it will search the image more aggressively for a supplemental. The scanner will try to scan the supplemental if it is present but if that fails, the main barcode will be returned.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_379" value="378or379">
                        <DESC>Auto-discriminates supplemental for upc/ean codes starting with 378 or 379. Will disable reading of supplementals for any other upc/ean barcodes not starting with these values. The supplemental will be scanned if present but if scanning fails then the main barcode will be returned.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_979" value="978or979">
                        <DESC>Auto-discriminates supplemental for upc/ean codes starting with 978 or 979. Will disable reading of supplementals for any other upc/ean barcodes not starting with these values. The supplemental will be scanned if present but if scanning fails then the main barcode will be returned.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCEAN_439" value="414or419or434or439">
                        <DESC>Auto-discriminates supplemental for upc/ean codes starting with 414 or 419 or 434 or 439. Will disable reading of supplementals for any other upc/ean barcodes not starting with these values. The supplemental will be scanned if present but if scanning fails then the main barcode will be returned.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upca" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for UPCA barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcaPreamble" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Controls the preamble applied to the UPCA barcode.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCA_PREAMBLE_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Applies no preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCA_PREAMBLE_SYSTEMCHAR" value="systemChar">
                        <DESC>Applies system character preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCA_PREAMBLE_COUNTRY" value="countryAndSystemChars">
                        <DESC>Applies both system and country code preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upcaReportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned UPCA barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce0" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for UPCE0 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce0convertToUpca" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, scanned UPCE0 barcodes will be converted to UPCA and UPCA parameters used.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce0preamble" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Controls the preamble applied to the UPCE0 barcode.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE0_PREAMBLE_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Applies no preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE0_PREAMBLE_SYSTEMCHAR" value="systemChar">
                        <DESC>Applies system character preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE0_PREAMBLE_COUNTRY" value="countryAndSystemChars">
                        <DESC>Applies both system and country code preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce0reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned UPCE0 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce1" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for UPCE1 barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce1convertToUpca" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, scanned UPCE1 barcodes will be converted to UPCA and UPCA parameters used.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce1preamble" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Controls the preamble applied to the UPCE1 barcode.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE1_PREAMBLE_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>Applies no preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE1_PREAMBLE_SYSTEMCHAR" value="systemChar">
                        <DESC>Applies system character preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="UPCE1_PREAMBLE_COUNTRY" value="countryAndSystemChars">
                        <DESC>Applies both system and country code preamble to the bar code.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="upce1reportCheckDigit" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, the barcode check digit(s) will be reported for scanned UPCE1 barcodes.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="webcode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Enables or disables the symbology for Webcode barcodes. If your application does not expect to scan this symbology you should disable it to improve scanning performance. Deprecated in Android 4.1 (Jelly Bean).</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="webcodeDecodeGtSubtype" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>2.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Not all scanning engines support all symbologies or all symbology properties</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the GT Webcode subtype will be decoded. Deprecated in Android 4.1 (Jelly Bean).</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>

            <!--  RSM Properties  -->
            <PROPERTY name="rsmModelNumber" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Ring scanner model number.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmSerialNumber" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Ring scanner serial number.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmDateOfManufacture" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Ring scanner date of manufacture as DDMMYY.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmDateOfService" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Ring scanner date of service as DDMMYY.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothAddress" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Bluetooth address as FF:FF:FF:FF:FF:FF where FF is a hex number.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmFirmwareVersion" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Scanner's operating system version.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmDeviceClass" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The device class of the ring scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBatteryStatus" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Indicates the status of the remote scanner's battery, will be one of 'unknown', 'full', 'medium', 'empty', 'chargingFullRate', 'chargingHalfRate', 'chargingTrickle' or 'discharging'</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBatteryCapacity" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The remaining capacity of the battery, in the range 0 to 100. 'unknown' will be returned if the capacity could not be determined, for example if the scanner had no battery.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBatteryId" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" readOnly="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>One of 'simple', 'double', 'disabled' or 'unknown'</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothAuthentication" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>True if authentication is required.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothEncryption" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>True if encryption is required.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothPinCode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Up to 5 character PIN code used for Bluetooth authentication.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothPinCodeType" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>'UseStored' will use the PIN code stored in the memory of the ring scanner, by default '12345'. 'PromptUser' indicates that the ring scanner should be used to scan 5 alpha numeric barcodes to define the PIN, eg. "1", "2", "3", "4", "5" (for PIN 12345). This parameter is not saved permanently on the ring scanner.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothReconnectionAttempts" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>How long the scanner tries to re-establish connection if it goes out of range, in seconds. This value must be a multiple of 5 and in the range 30 to 60 seconds.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothBeepOnReconnectAttempt" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>When true, scanner will emit 5 beeps every 5 seconds whilst re-connection in progress.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothHidAutoReconnect" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>'neverReconnect', 'reconnectOnData' or 'reconnectImmediately'</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothFriendlyName" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Friendly Bluetooth name, e.g. 'MyBTScanner'</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothInquiryMode" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>To use a general inquiry mode, 'general' else, 'limited'</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmBluetoothAutoReconnect" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Bluetooth reconnection scheme.</DESC>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="RSM_AUTORECONNECT_NONE" value="none">
                        <DESC>No scheme.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RSM_AUTORECONNECT_ON_POWER" value="onPower">
                        <DESC>When powered on.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RSM_AUTORECONNECT_ON_OUT_OF_RANGE" value="onOutOfRange">
                        <DESC>When device goes out of range.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="RSM_AUTORECONNECT_ON_POWER_OUT_OF_RANGE" value="onPowerOutOfRange">
                        <DESC>When powered on or when the device goes out of range.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmForceSavePairingBarcode" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Force saving the barcode assigned to the device to which the scanner has been paired.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmLowBatteryIndication" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Whether or not the ring scanner should give a low battery indication.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmLowBatteryIndicationCycle" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Low battery indication cycle time, in seconds. Must be one of 15, 30, 60, 90 or 120.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmScanLineWidth" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>The laser scan line width, 'wide' or 'narrow'.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmGoodScansDelay" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Delay between good scans in proximity continuous mode, measured in milliseconds. Range 0 to 15000. This value must be a multiple of 100.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmDecodeFeedback" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If true, the remote scanner beeps and illuminates its green LED on a successful decode.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmIgnoreCode128Usps" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Feature for ignoring Code 128 barcodes beginning with 420 and 421.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmScanTriggerWakeup" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Scanner trigger will wakeup the device from a low power state.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmMems" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If you press the trigger on an RSM scanner, proximity enabled will be turned off, even though it still reports its self as being turned on if you query the property. In order to use ProximityEnable you need to also have Mems enabled, this is the motion sensor and if you disable Mems the scanner will not function.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmProximityEnable" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If you press the trigger on an RSM scanner, proximity enabled will be turned off, even though it still reports its self as being turned on if you query the property. In order to use ProximityEnable you need to also have Mems enabled, this is the motion sensor and if you disable Mems the scanner will not function.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmProximityContinuous" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Proximity continuous mode.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmProximityDistance" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specify the distance for the proximity feature as 'short', 'medium' or 'long' </DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmPagingEnable" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Specify whether paging the device is enabled.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
            <PROPERTY name="rsmPagingBeepSequence" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Range 0 to 15 to specify the pattern for the paging beep sequence.</DESC>
            </PROPERTY>
        </PROPERTIES>

        <METHODS>
            <METHOD name="enumerate" access="STATIC" hasCallback="optional">
                <DESC>Used to gain access to all scanner objects present on the device. For consumer devices you will most likely only have a single scanner, your device's camera but Enterprise grade hardware may have two or more scanners attached.</DESC>
                <BACKWARDS_COMPATIBILITY state="false">
                    <DESC>This method replaces Barcode.enumerate from RhoElements 2.2 and takes a different prototype. Enumerate now returns an array of objects which can be used to control the specific scanner instance whereas previously it took a callback which returned the 'name' and 'id' of scanners present on the device.</DESC>
                </BACKWARDS_COMPATIBILITY>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS,WP8</PLATFORM>
                <CALLBACK type="ARRAY">
                    <DESC>Array of Barcode objects, one for each hardware scanner on the device. Methods and properties can be set separately on each scanner but if you are using one scanner you must first disable it before being able to use another scanner on the same device.</DESC>
                    <PARAM type="SELF_INSTANCE"/>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>
            <METHOD name="enable" hasCallback="optional">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Scanners which support a hardware or software trigger to invoke the scan.</APPLIES>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE,Android</PLATFORM>
                <DESC>Enabling the scanner puts it in a state where it will respond to the trigger (on devices with a hardware trigger) or will accept a command to initiate a soft scan (start method). Scanned barcodes will be available to the application through the callback provided to this method. Only one scanner on the device can be enabled at any one time, to switch between the imager and camera scanners (for example) then first disable the currently enabled scanner. If you do not specify a callback to this method you will received the scanned data as keystrokes. Note that it is necessary to enable the scanner on WM/CE devices prior to being able to retrieve the state of properties.</DESC>
                <BACKWARDS_COMPATIBILITY state="false">
                    <DESC>This method replaces Barcode.enable from RhoElements 2.2 and takes a different prototype, no longer taking a 'deviceName' parameter this method can now be called on the individual scanner instances returned by Barcode.enumerate to control which hardware scanner on the device is enabled. Please consider using Barcode.take if you only require a 'single shot' scan and Barcode.enable if your user will be using the trigger to return scan events.</DESC>
                </BACKWARDS_COMPATIBILITY>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="propertyMap" type="HASH" propertyHash="true">
                        <DESC>Provide a set of properties to configure the scanner, for example enable specific symbologies or check digits.</DESC>
                        <CAN_BE_NIL>
                            <DESC>Not providing properties to this function will use the scanner's default properties, or those previously set on the Scanner instance.</DESC>
                        </CAN_BE_NIL>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
                <CALLBACK type="HASH">
                    <DESC>Not providing a callback to be invoked when a barcode is scanned will result in that barcode being output as keystrokes.</DESC>
                    <PARAMS>
                        <PARAM name="data" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The data decoded by the scanner or imaging device.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="source" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The source device and human readable decoder type of the decoded barcode or symbol.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="type" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>Hex value representing the decoder type.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="time" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The time at which the decode occurred (hh:mm:ss)</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="length" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The length of the decoded barcode or symbol.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="direction" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The direction the barcode was scanned, either forward, reverse or unavailable.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAMS>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="registerBluetoothStatus" hasCallback="mandatory">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>If you are using an RS507 barcode scanner you can register to receive connected or disconnected events through this method.</DESC>
                <CALLBACK type="HASH">
                    <PARAMS>
                        <PARAM name="status" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The message describing the bluetooth connection: BluetoothConnected, BluetoothDisconnected or BTScanAssociationBarcode. See below for further descriptions.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAMS>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="start" hasCallback="none">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' scanners</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Performs a soft trigger start, initiating a scan without pressing the hardware trigger. If the scan does not result in a decode it is necessary to perform a soft stop before another soft start.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE,Android</PLATFORM>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="stop" hasCallback="none">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' scanners</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Performs a soft trigger stop.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE,Android</PLATFORM>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="disable" hasCallback="none">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' scanners</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Disables the barcode scanner. This reverts the scanner to its default state and flushes any current decoder settings.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE,Android</PLATFORM>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="barcode_recognize" hasCallback="none" deprecated="true">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>iOS, Android</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES>iOS/Android software recognizer</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Recognizes a barcode on an image. Returns a string with recognized code, or empty string if the barcode is not recognized.</DESC>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="imageFilePath" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>Path to the image that contains the barcode to be recognized.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
                <RETURN type="STRING">
                    <DESC>String with recognized code, or empty string if the barcode is not recognized.</DESC>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="getSupportedProperties" hasCallback="optional">
                <DESC>Return array of properties supported by this scanner.</DESC>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' scanners</APPLIES>
                <RETURN type="ARRAY">
                    <DESC>Array of property names supported by this scanner.</DESC>
                    <PARAM type="STRING"/>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="take" hasCallback="mandatory">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <DESC>Enable the scanner and start capturing the barcode automatically. On Symbol Technologies' devices the amount of time to scan the barcode is defined by the scanTimeout property. On iPhone and Android if a barcode is found, the user can confirm barcode recognition, or continue to try to recognize the barcode. When the user confirms or cancels, the callback is called. Once the callback has been called the barcode hardware is disabled.This method will work only on scanners which support soft scan.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS,WP8</PLATFORM>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="propertyMap" type="HASH" propertyHash="true">
                        <DESC>Provide a set of properties to configure the scanner, for example enable specific symbologies or check digits.</DESC>
                        <CAN_BE_NIL>
                            <DESC>Not providing properties to this function will use the scanner's default properties, or those previously set on the Scanner instance.</DESC>
                        </CAN_BE_NIL>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
                <CALLBACK type="HASH">
                    <PARAMS>
                        <PARAM name="barcode" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>The data decoded by the scanner or imaging device.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="status" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>Whether or not the barcode was successfully scanned, status will be 'ok' or 'cancel'</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAMS>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="take_barcode"  deprecated="true" productException="eb">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <APPLIES>iOS/Android software recognizer</APPLIES>
                <PLATFORM>iOS,WP8</PLATFORM>
                <DESC>Deprecated old method for Barcode.take().</DESC>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="rubyCallbackURL" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>Ruby callback URL.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                    <PARAM name="propertyMap" type="HASH" propertyHash="true">
                        <DESC>Provide a set of properties to configure the scanner, for example enable specific symbologies or check digits.</DESC>
                        <CAN_BE_NIL>
                            <DESC>Not providing properties to this function will use the scanner's default properties, or those previously set on the Scanner instance.</DESC>
                        </CAN_BE_NIL>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="commandRemoteScanner" hasCallback="none">
                <VER_INTRODUCED>4.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
                <APPLIES msiOnly="true">Symbol Technologies' Bluetooth barcode scanners, model RS507</APPLIES>
                <DESC>Instruct the connected RS507 scanner to perform some action.</DESC>
                <PARAMS>
                    <PARAM name="command" type="STRING">
                        <DESC>The action the RS507 scanner should perform, can be 'Disconnect' which disconnects the bluetooth RS507; 'unpair' which unpairs the RS507 from the device for association with another device; 'StartPaging' or 'StopPaging' which will cause the RS507 scanner to start or stop emitting a beep, to allow it to be located.</DESC>
                    </PARAM>
                </PARAMS>
            </METHOD>

        </METHODS>

        <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
        <PLATFORM>Android, iOS, WM</PLATFORM>
        <REMARKS>
            <REMARK title="Bluetooth Scanner Overview">
                <DESC>
Once associated with the Device a Bluetooth Scanner will remain associated even after losing the BT connection. In order to associate a different Bluetooth scanner with the device it is necessary to scan the 'unpairing' barcode and then invoke the 'disabled' method followed by the 'enabled' method, this will allow you to scan the BT association barcode with a different scanner. You can override this default behavior using the disconnectBtOnDisable property.

The following messages will be received from the Bluetooth Scanner in the bluetoothStatus event:

**'BTScanAssociationBarcode'**

Means the device is ready to be associated with a BT scanner. You must scan the
association barcode. It is only necessary to scan the association
barcode when you first associate a scanner with the device, this pairing will be remembered until
you scan the unpairing barcode.

**'BluetoothConnected'**

The remote scanner has successfully connected to the device.

**'BluetoothDisconnected'**

The remote scanner has become disconnected from the device, this may be due to loss of battery, being out
of range or scanning the 'unpairing' barcode. The scanner will attempt to reconnect automatically for
a period of time once it regains power or goes out of range, if it fails to reconnect after the specified
timeout the reconnect button on the device should be pushed. Once the unpairing barcode is scanned
it is necessary to disable the scanner and then re-enable it before another scanner can be associated.
                </DESC>
            </REMARK>
            <REMARK title="Viewfinder Position Parameters">
                <DESC>
On Symbol Technologies' scanners the scanner viewfinder window is not infinitely resizable, when setting ViewFinderX, ViewFinderY, ViewFinderWidth and ViewFinderHeight ensure you do not exceed the size of the screen and it is recommended to use the same aspect ratio as your device. For applications designed to handle screen rotation it is recommended to use a scan window whose longest side will fit within both the screen width and screen height. If your viewfinder position fails to be applied it is recommended you query your log file to see which parameter is causing trouble, or reposition the window away from the edges of the screen.
                </DESC>
            </REMARK>

            <REMARK title="Scanning and Camera Interaction">
                <DESC>In some device configurations the scanner and camera share the same hardware. Where two modules share the same physical hardware they cannot be enabled simultaneously, in this circumstance once the scanner is enabled it must be disabled before the camera can be used, and vice versa.</DESC>
            </REMARK>

            <REMARK title="Get Scanner Properties">
                <DESC>On WM/CE, it is first necessary to enable the scanner before most of the properties can be retrieved. The case of scanner properties will differ across platforms. On WM/CE, some of the scanner properties are not exposed to set but can be retrieved. On Android, only supported scanner properties can be retrieved in "getAllProperties" method.</DESC>
            </REMARK>

        <REMARK title="Set Scanner Properties">
                <DESC>On WM/CE, for some properties, it is first necessary to apply those properties before enabling the scanner.</DESC>
            </REMARK>

        <REMARK title="Android Camera Barcode limitation">
                <DESC>As google barcode scanning library(Zxing library) supported only in Landscape mode. Barcode scanning window only appears at centre of screen in Landscape mode.</DESC>
            </REMARK>
            
            <REMARK title="DataWedge Interaction With Native Apps" productException="eb">
                <DESC>In order to use the scanner with RhoElements Native Apps you will need to either disable DataWedge or create a DataWedge profile for your app.
**Disabling Datawedge**

1. Start the DataWedge app
2. Click the menu button > "Settings" and untick "DataWedge enabled".

**RhoElements Datawedge Profile**

1. Install your RhoElements native app,
2. Start the DataWedge app
3. Click the menu button > "New Profile" and enter a name,
4. Click on the link to the new profile in the profile list,
5. Click on "Associated apps" in the "Applications" section,
6. Click the menu button > "New app/activity",
7. Select the package name for your app,
8. Select "*",
9. Click the "Back" capacitive button,
10. Make sure the "Profile enabled" checkbox is ticked.
11. Uncheck all three "Enabled" checkboxes under the sections of:
    "Barcode input", "Keystroke output" and "Intent output".
                </DESC>
            </REMARK>
        </REMARKS>

        <EXAMPLES>
           <EXAMPLE title="Scan barcodes with the default scanner">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Getting started with barcode scanning is very straightforward. If you do not need to customize the defaults, you need very little code.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
def scan_using_default_scanner
  # Scan with default options
  Rho::Barcode.take({}, url_for(:action => :scan_received))
end

def scan_received
  # Did we actually find a barcode ?
  # If status is not 'ok', the scan was canceled
  if @params["status"] == "ok"
    Rho::Log.info(@params["barcode"],"Barcode result")
  else
    Rho::Log.info("canceled", "Barcode result")
  end
end
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
function scan_using_default_scanner(){
  // Scan with default options
  Rho.Barcode.take({}, scan_received);
}

function scan_received(params){
  // Did we actually find a barcode ?
  // If status is not 'ok', the scan was canceled

    if (params["status"]=="ok") {
        alert('Barcode scanning complete. Scanned barcode: '+params["barcode"]);
    } else {
        alert('Barcode scanning aborted');
    }
    Rho.Barcode.stop();
}
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Select which scanner to use">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>By default, Rho::Barcode will select a hardware scanner if present on the device. If you want to let the user choose which scanner to use at any particular time, you must enumerate the available scanners and select one from the set.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
# ---------------
# controller.rb
# ---------------

def choose_scanner
  # Obtain list of available scanners on the system. Devices without a hardware scanner will return a software-based recognizer
  $scanners = Rho::Barcode.enumerate
  render
end

def scan_using_chosen_scanner
  # receive an integer as parameter, which represent the number of the scanner we wish to use
  scanner = $scanners[@params["scannerIndex"].to_i]
  scanner.take({}, url_for(:action => :scan_received_callback))
end

def scan_received_callback
  # Did we actually find a barcode ?
  # If status is not 'ok', the scan was canceled
  if @params["status"] == "ok"
    Rho::Log.info(@params["barcode"],"Barcode result")
  else
    Rho::Log.info("canceled", "Barcode result")
  end
end


# ---------------
# choose_scanner.erb
# ---------------
<ul data-role="listview">
  <% $scanners.each_with_index do |scanner, index| %>
    <li><a href="<%= url_for(:action => :scan_using_chosen_scanner, :query => {:scanner_index => index}) %>"><%= scanner.friendlyName %></li>
  <% end %>
</ul>
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
var scanners;

function choose_scanner(){

  // Enumerate returns an array of scanner objects
  // Devices without a hardware scanner will return a software-based recognizer
  scanners = Rho.Barcode.enumerate();
}

function scan_using_chosen_scanner(scanner_index) {
    var scanner = scanners[scanner_index];
    scanner.take({}, scan_received_callback);
}

function scan_received_callback(params){
  // Did we actually find a barcode?
  // If status is not 'ok' the scan is canceled
  if (params["status"]=="ok") {
            alert('Barcode scanning complete. Scanned barcode: '+params["barcode"]);
        } else {
            alert('Barcode scanning aborted');
        }
        Rho.Barcode.stop();
}
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Set recognized symbologies">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Specify which symbologies the barcode scanner must recognize.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
# For the purpose of this example, let's say our application only needs to recognize one type of barcode.
# In that case, we will disable all decoders...
Rho::Barcode.allDecoders = false
# ... and enable only the one we are interested in:
Rho::Barcode.upca = true
# All other barcode symbologies will be ignored
Rho::Barcode.take({}, url_for(:action => :scan_received_callback))

                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
// For the purpose of this example, let's say our application only needs to recognize one type of barcode.
// In that case, we will disable all decoders...
Rho.Barcode.allDecoders = false;
// ... and enable only the one we are interested in:
Rho.Barcode.upca = true;
// All other barcode symbologies will be ignored
Rho.Barcode.take({}, scan_received_callback);
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Control scanner properties">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>Examples of setting barcode scanner properties.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
# There are over 200 properties to fine-tune the barcode scanner functionality and adapt it to suit your application.
# Almost all properties depend on the scanner hardware for support, please check the documentation to see if your device
# supports a particular setting

# Here are examples of setting some of the properties. The documentation lists the acceptable values for each of them

# Aiming mode (visual cue):
Rho::Barcode.aimMode = "none"
Rho::Barcode.aimMode = "dot"
Rho::Barcode.aimMode = "slab"
Rho::Barcode.aimMode = "reticle"

# Aiming type (processing mode):
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "trigger"
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "timedHold"
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "timedRelease"
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "presentation"
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "pressAndRelease"
Rho::Barcode.aimType = "continuousRead"

# Generate an "Enter" keypress after a barcode is recognized. Useful for sending forms automatically after a scan
Rho::Barcode.autoEnter = true

# Select the beam width of the scanner (only supported on some devices)
Rho::Barcode.beamWidth = "normal"
Rho::Barcode.beamWidth = "narrow"
Rho::Barcode.beamWidth = "wide"
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
// There are over 200 properties to fine-tune the barcode scanner functionality and adapt it to suit your application.
// Almost all properties depend on the scanner hardware for support, please check the documentation to see if your device
// supports a particular setting

// Here are examples of setting some of the properties. The documentation lists the acceptable values for each of them

// Aiming mode (visual cue):
Rho.Barcode.aimMode = "none";
Rho.Barcode.aimMode = "dot";
Rho.Barcode.aimMode = "slab";
Rho.Barcode.aimMode = "reticle";

// Aiming type (processing mode):
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "trigger";
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "timedHold";
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "timedRelease";
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "presentation";
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "pressAndRelease";
Rho.Barcode.aimType = "continuousRead";

// Generate an "Enter" keypress after a barcode is recognized. Useful for sending forms automatically after a scan
Rho.Barcode.autoEnter = true;

// Select the beam width of the scanner (only supported on some devices)
Rho.Barcode.beamWidth = "normal";
Rho.Barcode.beamWidth = "narrow";
Rho.Barcode.beamWidth = "wide";
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
           </EXAMPLE>
           <EXAMPLE title="Change audible options">
            <SECTIONS>
              <SECTION>
               <DESC>You can customize or eliminate the beep that the device emits when a barcode is recognized. Support and valid ranges for these values depend on the device.</DESC>
               <CODE>
                <RUBY>
           <![CDATA[
# Maximum volume (default)
Rho::Barcode.decodeVolume = 5
# Low-pitched sound
Rho::Barcode.decodeFrequency = 1000
# One-second long
Rho::Barcode.decodeDuration = 1000

Rho::Barcode.take({}, url_for(:action => :scan_received_callback))
                   ]]>
                 </RUBY>
                <JAVASCRIPT>
           <![CDATA[
// Maximum volume (default)
Rho.Barcode.decodeVolume = 5;
// Low-pitched sound
Rho.Barcode.decodeFrequency = 1000;
// One-second long
Rho.Barcode.decodeDuration = 1000;

Rho.Barcode.take({}, scan_received_callback);
                   ]]>
                 </JAVASCRIPT>
               </CODE>
               </SECTION>
               </SECTIONS>
            </EXAMPLE>
        </EXAMPLES>
    </MODULE>
</API>
