<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>

<HELPPAGE>
	<FUNC>
		<NAME>addressBar</NAME>
		<PATH>Controls and Appearance</PATH>
		<TYPE>Module</TYPE>
		<SYNOPSIS>is used to set the parameters of the address bar. The address bar should only be used for debugging Hybrid applications and is not designed to be used as a replacement for a web browser address bar.  Press the 'Go' button or enter key to navigate to the typed URI.
		</SYNOPSIS>
			<SYNTAX>
				<USAGE>
					<EXAMPLE>&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" content="[parameter]"&gt;</EXAMPLE>
				</USAGE>                 
			</SYNTAX>
		<PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>left</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the X position of the address bar.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>0</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>				
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>top</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the Y position of the address bar.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>0</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
            <PARAM>
				<NAME>width</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the width of the address bar.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Most of the screen width</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>visibility</NAME>
                <VALUES>visible, hidden</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the visibility of the address bar</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Hidden</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
		</PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
		<EXAMPLES>
			<EXAMPLE>
				<DESC>The following example shows the address bar, sets the left and top coordinates to 50, and the width to 100.</DESC>
<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" Content="visibility:visible"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" Content="left:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" Content="top:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" Content="width:100"&gt;
</CODE>
			</EXAMPLE>
			<EXAMPLE>
			<DESC>The following example shows the address bar, sets the left and top coordinates to 0, and the width to 50.</DESC>
<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="AddressBar" Content="left:0; top:0; width:50"&gt;
</CODE>
			</EXAMPLE>
		</EXAMPLES>
		<REMARKS>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Default Positions</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>By default this control will be placed a the top of the screen.  On Windows Mobile if the 'FullScreen' configuration setting is disabled the control will need to be moved, otherwise it will appear beneath the task bar.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Switching to Other Applications</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>All controls are designed to be shown on top of RhoElements.  If you require to switch to an application other than RhoElements you should minimize RhoElements to ensure the buttons do not remain shown. (Not applicable to Android)</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Screen Orientation</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>When the screen orientation changes, either using the ScreenOrientation tag or by rotating a device with hardware support, the command areas will automatically move and resize to fit the new layout. However the buttons themselves are not moved and in some cases this may result in them being off the screen or not in the expected position. If so they must be moved manually by detecting the ScreenOrientationEvent.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Named Anchors</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>The address bar is not compatible with named anchors (page bookmarks) eg. &lt;a name="bookmark"/&gt;</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Use in Production</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>This API is designed for debugging your application only and should not be used in production</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
		</REMARKS>	
		<ADDITIONAL>
			<PLATFORM>All supported touch devices.</PLATFORM>
			<APPLIES>Persistent - Changes to this module will persist when navigating to a new page.</APPLIES>
			<REQ>None.</REQ>
			<VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
		</ADDITIONAL>
		<SEEALSO>
			<TOPIC>GoButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>StopButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>BackButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>SIPButton</TOPIC>			
			<TOPIC>ReloadButton</TOPIC>						
		</SEEALSO>
	</FUNC>
</HELPPAGE>
