<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>

<HELPPAGE>
	<FUNC>
		<NAME>homeButton</NAME>
		<PATH>Controls and Appearance</PATH>
		<TYPE>Module</TYPE>
		<SYNOPSIS>is used to set the parameters of the Home Button. When the home button is clicked RhoElements will navigate to the start page as defined in the configuration.</SYNOPSIS>
        <SYNTAX>
            <USAGE>
				<EXAMPLE>&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" content="[parameter]"&gt;</EXAMPLE>
            </USAGE>
        </SYNTAX>
        <PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>left</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the X position of the Home Button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>To the right of the address bar</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>top</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the Y position of the Home Button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>To the right of the address bar</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
            <PARAM>
				<NAME>height</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the height of the Home Button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Dependant on screen resolution</DEFAULT>
			 </PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>width</NAME>
                <VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the width of the Home Button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Dependant on screen resolution</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
            <PARAM>
				<NAME>imageUp</NAME>
                <VALUES>URL</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the image to be displayed when the Home Button is in the up state.  See Remarks.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Default image</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
            <NAME>imageDown</NAME>
				<VALUES>URL</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the image to be displayed when the Home Button is in the down state.  See Remarks.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Default image</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>visibility</NAME>
                <VALUES>Visible, Hidden</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the visibility of the Home button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Hidden</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
		</PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
		<EXAMPLES>
			<EXAMPLE>
				<DESC>The following example shows the Home button, sets its left and top coordinates to 50, and its width and height to 30 pixels.</DESC>
<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Visibility:Visible"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Left:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Top:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Width:30"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Height:30"&gt;
</CODE>
            </EXAMPLE>
            <EXAMPLE>
				<DESC>The following example shows the Home button, sets its width to 30 pixels, its left coordinate to 50, and displays the home_up.gif / home_down.gif image on it (resizing the images if necessary).</DESC>
<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="HomeButton" Content="Width:30; Left:50; ImageUp:url('http://myaddress/home_up.gif'); ImageDown:url('http://myaddress/home_down.gif'); Visibility:Visible"&gt;
</CODE>
            </EXAMPLE>
		</EXAMPLES>
		<REMARKS>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Use of Images on Buttons.</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>Images can be specified as local to the device or on an HTTP / FTP server, just specify the required protocol as part of your URL (file://\, HTTP:// and FTP://).  Image will be scaled to the size of the button.  JPEG and GIF images are only supported on WM devices.  Both CE and WM support BMP files.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Default Positions</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>By default this control will be placed a the top of the screen.  On Windows Mobile if the 'FullScreen' configuration setting is disabled the control will need to be moved, otherwise it will appear beneath the task bar.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Switching to Other Applications</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>All controls are designed to be shown on top of RhoElements.  If you require to switch to an application other than RhoElements you should minimize RhoElements to ensure the buttons do not remain shown. (Not applicable to Android)</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Screen Orientation</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>When the screen orientation changes, either using the ScreenOrientation tag or by rotating a device with hardware support, the command areas will automatically move and resize to fit the new layout. However the buttons themselves are not moved and in some cases this may result in them being off the screen or not in the expected position. If so they must be moved manually by detecting the ScreenOrientationEvent.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Use in Production</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>This API is designed for debugging your application only and should not be used in production</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
		</REMARKS>
		<ADDITIONAL>
			<PLATFORM>All supported touch devices.</PLATFORM>
			<APPLIES>Persistent - Changes to this module will persist when navigating to a new page.</APPLIES>
			<REQ>None.</REQ>
			<VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
		</ADDITIONAL>
		<SEEALSO>
			<TOPIC>GoButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>StopButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>AddressBar</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC>ReloadButton</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC RELPATH="../Key Handling/">KeyCapture</TOPIC>
			<TOPIC RELPATH="../Getting Started/">ConfigurationSettings</TOPIC>
		</SEEALSO>
	</FUNC>
</HELPPAGE>
