<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>

<HELPPAGE>
	<FUNC>
		<NAME>sipButton</NAME>
		<PATH>Controls and Appearance</PATH>
		<TYPE>Module</TYPE>
		<SYNOPSIS>is used to set the parameters of the SIP Button.  The SIPButton will toggle the display of the soft input panel allowing keyboard input via a stylus.
    </SYNOPSIS>
		<SYNTAX>
			<USAGE>
				<EXAMPLE>&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" content="[parameter]"&gt;</EXAMPLE>
			</USAGE>
		</SYNTAX>
		<PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>left</NAME>
				<VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the X position of the SIP button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Bottom right of the screen</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>top</NAME>
				<VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the Y position of the SIP button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Bottom right of the screen</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
            <PARAM>
				<NAME>height</NAME>
				<VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the height of the SIP button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Dependant on screen resolution</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
            <PARAM>
				<NAME>width</NAME>
				<VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the width of the SIP button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Dependant on screen resolution</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>imageUp</NAME>
				<VALUES>URL</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the image to be displayed when the SIP Button is in the up state. See Remarks.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Default image</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>imageDown</NAME>
				<VALUES>URL</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the image to be displayed when the SIP Button is in the down state. See Remarks.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Default image</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>
			<PARAM>
				<NAME>visibility</NAME>
                <VALUES>Visible, Hidden</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the visibility of the SIP button.</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Hidden.</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>				
		</PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
		<EXAMPLES>
			<EXAMPLE>
				<DESC>The following example shows the SIP button, sets its top and left coordinates to 50, and its width and height to 30 pixels.</DESC>
				<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="Visibility:Visible"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="Left:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="Top:50"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="Width:30"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="Height:30"&gt;
				</CODE>
			</EXAMPLE>
			<EXAMPLE>
			    <DESC>The following example shows the SIP button and displays the sip_up.gif / sip_down.gif image on it (resizing the image if necessary).</DESC>
				<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="SIPButton" Content="ImageUp:url('http://myaddress/sip_up.gif'); ImageDown:url('http://myaddress/sip_down.gif'); Visibility:Visible"&gt;
				</CODE>
            </EXAMPLE>
		</EXAMPLES>
		<REMARKS>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Use of Images on Buttons.</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>Images can be specified as local to the device or on an HTTP / FTP server, just specify the required protocol as part of your URL (file://\, HTTP:// and FTP://).  Image will be scaled to the size of the button.  JPEG and GIF images are only supported on WM devices.  Both CE and WM support BMP files.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Switching to Other Applications</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>All controls are designed to be shown on top of RhoElements.  If you require to switch to an application other than RhoElements you should minimize RhoElements to ensure the buttons do not remain shown. (Not applicable to Android devices) (Not applicable to Android devices).</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Screen Orientation</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>When the screen orientation changes, either using the ScreenOrientation tag or by rotating a device with hardware support, the command areas will automatically move and resize to fit the new layout. However the buttons themselves are not moved and in some cases this may result in them being off the screen or not in the expected position. If so they must be moved manually by detecting the ScreenOrientationEvent.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
		</REMARKS>
		<ADDITIONAL>
			<PLATFORM>All supported touch devices.</PLATFORM>
			<APPLIES>Persistent - Changes to this module will persist when navigating to a new page.</APPLIES>
			<REQ>None.</REQ>
			<VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
		</ADDITIONAL>
		<SEEALSO>
			<TOPIC>KeyState</TOPIC>						
			<TOPIC>ZoomTextButton</TOPIC>						
		</SEEALSO>
	</FUNC>
</HELPPAGE>
