<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>

<HELPPAGE>
	<FUNC>
		<NAME>topCommandArea</NAME>
		<PATH>Controls and Appearance</PATH>
		<TYPE>Module</TYPE>
		<SYNOPSIS>is used to set the parameters of the Top Command Area.  The top command area is a region at the top of the screen designed to hold RhoElements controls such as the address bar or Go button to separate them from the rest of the user application.</SYNOPSIS>
		<SYNTAX>
			<USAGE>
				<EXAMPLE>&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="TopCommandArea" content="[parameter]"&gt;</EXAMPLE>
			</USAGE>
		</SYNTAX>
    <PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
      <PARAM>
        <NAME>visibility</NAME>
        <VALUES>Visible, Hidden</VALUES>
        <DESC>Sets the visibility of the top command area.</DESC>
        <DEFAULT>Hidden.</DEFAULT>
      </PARAM>				
		<PARAM>
			<NAME>height</NAME>
			<VALUES>Positive number, representing pixels</VALUES>
				<DESC>Sets the height of the top command area</DESC>
				<DEFAULT>Slightly greater than the height of a buttons default height, which depends on the screen resolution.</DEFAULT>
			</PARAM>				
		<PARAM>
		<NAME>color</NAME>
        <VALUES>Color in the #RRGGBB format</VALUES>
		<DESC>The color to set the top command area to.</DESC>
		<DEFAULT>None. The default image is displayed by default.</DEFAULT>
	  </PARAM>

      <PARAM>
        <NAME>image</NAME>
        <VALUES>URL</VALUES>
        <DESC>Sets the image to be displayed on the top command area.  See Remarks.</DESC>
        <DEFAULT>Default image</DEFAULT>
      </PARAM>
		</PARAMS_WITH_ATTRIBUTES>
    
		<EXAMPLES>
			<EXAMPLE>
				<DESC>The following example shows the Top Command Area, sets the Height to 100 and background color to red</DESC>
<CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="TopCommandArea" Content="Visibility:Visible"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="TopCommandArea" Content="Height:100"&gt;
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="TopCommandArea" Content="Color:#FF0000"&gt;
</CODE>
			</EXAMPLE>
      <EXAMPLE>
        <DESC>The following example shows the Top Command Area, sets the height to 100 and displays image tca.gif on it (resizing the image if necessary)</DESC>
        <CODE>
&lt;META HTTP-Equiv="TopCommandArea" Content="Height:100; Visibility:Visible; Image:url('http://myaddress/tca.gif')"&gt;
        </CODE>
      </EXAMPLE>
      
		</EXAMPLES>
		<REMARKS>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Default Positions</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>By default this control will be placed a the top of the screen.  On Windows Mobile if the 'FullScreen' configuration setting is disabled the control will need to be moved, otherwise it will appear beneath the task bar.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Switching to Other Applications</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>All controls are designed to be shown on top of RhoElements.  If you require to switch to an application other than RhoElements you should minimize RhoElements to ensure the buttons do not remain shown. (Not applicable to Android devices)</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
			<COMMENT>
				<COMMENT_HEADING>Screen Orientation</COMMENT_HEADING>
				<COMMENT_DATA>When the screen orientation changes, either using the ScreenOrientation tag or by rotating a device with hardware support, the command areas will automatically move and resize to fit the new layout. However the buttons themselves are not moved and in some cases this may result in them being off the screen or not in the expected position. If so they must be moved manually by detecting the ScreenOrientationEvent.</COMMENT_DATA>
			</COMMENT>
		</REMARKS>	
		<ADDITIONAL>
			<PLATFORM>All supported devices.</PLATFORM>
			<APPLIES>Persistent - Changes to this module will persist when navigating to a new page.</APPLIES>
			<REQ>None.</REQ>
			<VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
		</ADDITIONAL>
		<SEEALSO>
			<TOPIC>BottomCommandArea</TOPIC>
		</SEEALSO>
	</FUNC>
</HELPPAGE>
