<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="pb_help.xsl"?>
<API>
    <MODULE name="Videocapture" parent="Rho" productException='eb'>
        <ALIASES>
            <ALIAS new="videocapture" deprecated="true"/>
        </ALIASES>
        <HELP_OVERVIEW>captures video files from the default camera device.Only the foreground application is given access to capture video, when an application is sent to the background any capture that is in progress will be canceled and it will automatically relinquish control of the video hardware. When brought back to the foreground, an application previously using the video capture will have its previous configuration (eg. name etc.) reapplied to the plug-in automatically. Please note that any file transfer that is in progress continues even if the application is sent to the background.</HELP_OVERVIEW>
        <MORE_HELP>
## Enabling the API
In order to use this API you must include the following extension in your `build.yml`
    :::ruby
    extensions: ["mediacapture"]

## JavaScript Usage
Be sure to review the [JavaScript API Usage](/guide/api_js) guide for important information about using this API in JavaScript.

## Ruby Usage
Be sure to review the [Ruby API Usage](/guide/api_ruby) guide for important information about using this API in Ruby.
        </MORE_HELP>
        <TEMPLATES>
            <DEFAULT_INSTANCE/> <!-- object has default static property, all methods can be call by static way (called from default instance), produce default(), set_default() methods -->
            <PROPERTY_BAG/> <!-- object has properties, produce getProps(), setProps() methods -->
        </TEMPLATES>

        <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS</PLATFORM>

        <PROPERTIES usePropertyBag="accessorsViaPropertyBag">
            <DESC>These properties are used for configuring video capture.</DESC>
             <PROPERTY name="duration" type="INTEGER" generateAccessors="true" default="5000">
                <DESC>Specifies the number of milliseconds of video to capture. This is the maximum number of milliseconds of video to capture when the 'start' method is called if not interrupted with the 'stop' method. The duration cannot be set to less than 1000 milliseconds, if a value of less than 1000 milliseconds is specified, the interval will be defaulted to 5000 milliseconds.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS</PLATFORM>
            </PROPERTY>

            <PROPERTY name="fileName" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true">
                <DESC>The path and name of the file that the video is saved to locally on the device. When the video capture completes the file is saved in the root directory of the device (In case of Android this is the external storage directory). For example, if the user specifies '/video/file1' then the file gets saved as '/mnt/sdcard/video/file1.mp4' in Android, and as '\video\file1.mov' on Windows. The file extension should not be provided as this is determined by the platform (.mp4 in Android and .mov in Windows). On iOS you'll need to provide the entire path, including the extension, which should be .MOV.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS</PLATFORM>
            </PROPERTY>

            <PROPERTY name="saveToGallery" type="BOOLEAN" generateAccessors="true">
                <DESC>Specifies whether or not to save the recorded video file into the device gallery.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
            </PROPERTY>

            <PROPERTY name="resolution" type="STRING" generateAccessors="true" default="HIGH">
                <DESC>The resolution of the video file to be captured.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android</PLATFORM>
                <VALUES>
                    <VALUE constName="LOW" value="low">
                        <DESC>Low resolution.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                    <VALUE constName="HIGH" value="high">
                        <DESC>High resolution.</DESC>
                    </VALUE>
                </VALUES>
            </PROPERTY>
        </PROPERTIES>

        <METHODS>
            <METHOD name="start" hasCallback="optional" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Starts capturing video until either 'stop' is received, or 'duration' is reached. NOTE: On Android this meta tag wouldn't immediately start recording and presents a preview window with controls (start, stop and cancel) for recording.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM, CE, Android, iOS</PLATFORM>
                <RETURN>
                    <DESC>Not providing a callback to be invoked will result in that file is saved only locally and file is not transfered.</DESC>
                </RETURN>
                <CALLBACK>
                    <PARAMS>
                        <PARAM name="transferResult" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>Reports success or failure of transfer.</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="fileName" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>Name of the saved file (absolute path).</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                        <PARAM name="fileSize" type="STRING">
                            <DESC>Size of the saved file in kilobytes (KB).</DESC>
                        </PARAM>
                    </PARAMS>
                </CALLBACK>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="stop" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Stops capturing video and either saves the file locally, or transfers it to a remote server. NOTE: This is not applicable for Android and iOS as the video capture window is full screen and provides a button to stop the video capture. Please note that the file transfer happens as specified even if we don't call the stop method.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="cancel" runInThread="ui">
                <DESC>Stops capturing video and discards any captured video data. No file transfer takes place if the video capture is canceled. NOTE: This is not applicable for Android and iOS as the video capture window is full screen and provides a button to cancel the video capture.</DESC>
                <PLATFORM>WM</PLATFORM>
            </METHOD>

            <METHOD name="enumerate" access="STATIC" hasCallback="optional">
                <DESC>Enumerates all the available cameras for capturing video.</DESC>
                <RETURN type="ARRAY">
                    <DESC>Array of video capture objects.</DESC>
                    <PARAM type="SELF_INSTANCE"/>
                </RETURN>
            </METHOD>
        </METHODS>

        <VER_INTRODUCED>1.0.0</VER_INTRODUCED>
        <PLATFORM>Android, WM, iOS</PLATFORM>

        <REMARKS>
            <REMARK title="Memory requirements">
                <DESC>Once duration has been reached the video file will be saved or transferred. Calling 'stop' once this has occurred will have no effect. A Video Capture will fail if there is not sufficient space on the device's filesystem to store it.</DESC>
            </REMARK>

            <REMARK title="File Formats">
                <DESC>The output file format on Android is MP4 and on Windows is WMV.</DESC>
            </REMARK>
            <REMARK title="SDCard Access">
                <DESC>Extensions which came from RhoElements (i.e. AudioCapture) that could possibly write files to external storage will require "write SD card" permissions as part of the extension's AndroidManifest. You cannot remove the ability to write to the SD card as it would cause the extension to malfunction. Therefore, the capability has already been granted on build, and any capability added by you will be ignored. This being the case, the following extensions will always be able to write to the SD card by default.</DESC>
            </REMARK>
        </REMARKS>

        <EXAMPLES>
            <EXAMPLE title="Basic Example">
                <SECTIONS>
                    <SECTION>
                        <DESC>The default video capture object on the device is enabled when the index view is loaded.</DESC>
                        <CODE>
                            <RUBY><![CDATA[
#/app/Model
def index
    Rho::Videocapture.fileName = '/RhoVideoCapture'
    Rho::Videocapture.duration = 30000
    Rho::Videocapture.start(url_for(:action => :mysaveevent))
end
  def mysaveevent
       puts "Save params: #{@params}"
       puts "Result is #{@params['transferResult']}"
       puts "Name is #{@params['fileName']}"
       puts "Size is #{@params['size']}"
  end
]]>
                            </RUBY>
                        </CODE>
                    </SECTION>
                    <SECTION>
                        <DESC>Then in index.erb file:</DESC>
                        <CODE>
                            <HTML><![CDATA[
<script type="text/javascript" charset="utf-8" src="/public/js/application.js"></script>
<div data-role="page">
  <div data-role="header" data-position="inline">
    <h1>Videocapture Extension Test</h1>
    <a href="<%= Rho::RhoConfig.start_path %>" class="ui-btn-left" data-icon="home" data-direction="reverse"
       <%= "data-ajax='false'" if is_bb6 %>>Home</a>
  </div>
    <div id='output'>Output goes here</div>
  <div data-role="content">
    <ul data-role="listview">
        <%= link_to 'Run Test', { :action => :run_test }%>
        <a href="javascript:Test()">Run Test JS</a>
        <a href="videocapture_ajax.htm">Videocapture (Ajax Requests)</a>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
]]>
                            </HTML>
                        </CODE>
                    </SECTION>
                </SECTIONS>
            </EXAMPLE>
        </EXAMPLES>
    </MODULE>
</API>